<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Digital Compilation of Letters from 1942</title>
            <!-- do we have one header for all letters or one for each doc? -->
            <author corresp="#JM">James Mills</author>
            <author corresp="#DB">Doreen Brown</author>
            <principal>Hannah Mills</principal>
            <!-- what else do we want to include in title stmt? e.g. respstmt? -->
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Borås</publisher>
            <!-- publisher still to be decided authority tag? distributor tags? -->
            <date>March 2022</date>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">
                  <!-- do we want to have a CC licence? -->
                  <p> Transcription distributed under a CC-BY-SA 4.0 license. </p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>A post-it with a simple example phrase on it</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="WD" medium="blue-ink">Original text in blue ink, written by Wout
               Dillen.</handNote>
         </handNotes>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface xml:id="postit01">
         <figure>
            <label>Post-It 01</label>
            <figDesc> A photograph of a post-it with a simple example phrase. </figDesc>
            <graphic xml:id="postit01_full" url="assets/img/documents/postit01.png"/>
            <graphic xml:id="postit01_thumb" url="assets/img/documents/postit01_thumb.png"/>
         </figure>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
   <text>

      <body>
         <div n="1" type="letter">
            <pb facs="#postit01"/>
            <!-- insert correct image here -->
            <head>Letter 1 - Saturday Evening</head>
            <p rend="top left">METHODIST GUILD <lb/>
               <hi rend="u">HOLIDAYS</hi>.</p>
            <lb/>
            <p>TELEPHONE DUNOON 234.</p>
            <!-- check how to correctly mark up the letter header metamark?-->
            <div>
               <opener>
                  <time rend="right">Saturday <hi rend="u">Evening</hi>.</time>
                  <salute rend="left">My Dear Doreen,</salute>
               </opener>
            </div>
            <div>
               <p>Dhalling Mhor doesn’t seem like Dhalling <lb/> Mhor now you are not here. You had
                  become so <lb/> much a part of the life here, so far as I was <lb/> concerned,
                  that things seem a bit dead now<lb/> you have gone.</p>
               <p>By this time you will be at home<lb/> or very near home (time six o’clock) and
                  looking mournfully at the weather; it’s bound to be raining<lb/> in Manchester as
                  it is here still. You have been<lb/> much in my thoughts as you made the
                  beastly<lb/> railway journey and I kept saying to myself, “They<lb/> will have
                  reached Glasgow now; they will be on the<lb/> M/C train now.”</p>
               <p> I can’t say how much I’ve missed<lb/> you today. I’ve wondered round a bit on my own,<lb/>
                  <!-- look up page break -->and played cards a bit with the older generation,<lb/>
                  and slept a bit. Harry and Ellie, Jack and<lb/> Jean wanted me to go to the
                  pictures with<lb/> them but as they were going to see Gert and<lb/>
                  Daisy<!-- look up how to mark film name --> I declined the invitation.</p>
               <p>I’ve moved my belongings into room 13<lb/> and find it’s a delightful room with a
                  nice<lb/> thick carpet which is much better than the<lb/> thin, loose mats to
                  which you and I have<lb/> been used to hitherto. No doubt John<lb/> and I will do
                  much talking about Ruby<lb/> and ______ (well don’t be surprised if you ears<lb/>
                  burn a bit, too).</p>
               <p>There was a letter here for Poppy.<lb/> Mr. Henderson and I were re-addressing
                  them and it’s<lb/> been sent on to your house; your address was<lb/> the one given
                  in the visitors book; remember?<lb/> You will be able to pass it on to Poppy.<lb/>
                  You might note <!-- look up note for squiggle --> that the stamp is placed<lb/><!-- insert page break -->
                  <!-- insert header -->
                  <!-- insert metamark for page number --> crookedly and no doubt will bring a blush
                  to<lb/> her cheek - that is, if it’s from the right<lb/> person.</p>
               <p>The new guests have been rolling up<lb/> looking
                  <!-- insert rend crossed out -->bedg bedraggled, weary, worn and wet; but<lb/> I
                  haven’t got to know any of them yet,<lb/> and there are more coming I know.<lb/>
               </p>
               <p>Let me know, Doreen, how you got<lb/> along today. You know, surely, that I
                  shall<lb/> always be glad to hear from you and don’t<lb/> forget the tea. I looked
                  in my diary and<lb/> found that Sept. 7th. is the date of the Harvest<lb/>
                  Festival Lecture at the mission so please <!-- look up misspelling -->stear<lb/>
                  clear of that date, won’t you? I shall<lb/> count the days to Sept. with keen
                  anticipation.<lb/> Don’t do too much work next week if you<lb/> don’t feel like
                  it; I’ll give you permission to<lb/>
                  <!-- insert page break --> slack but don’t let the boss see you. Think<lb/> of me
                  on the hills (that’s where I shan’t<lb/> be if it keeps raining).<lb/>
               </p>
               <p>I ought to have said this morning,<lb/> ‘Thanks for helping to make my week’s
                  stay<lb/> at Dhalling Mhor such a happy one.’ This<lb/> second week will not be as
                  happy as the<lb/> first, I know. Do accept my thanks,<lb/> now. I feel so glad
                  that the week<lb/> afforded to us the opportunity of each other’s<lb/> company
                  &amp; I hope we shall continue the<lb/> friendship.<lb/>
               </p>
               <div>
                  <closer>
                     <salute>Every good wish to you, Doreen.<lb/> Your very sincere friend,</salute>
                     <signed>
                        <hi rend="u"/>Jim.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
