<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Digital Compilation of Letters from 1942</title>
            <!-- do we have one header for all letters or one for each doc? -->
            <author corresp="#JM">James Mills</author>
            <author corresp="#DB">Doreen Brown <addName type="marriedName">Doreen Mills</addName>
            </author>
            <principal>Hannah Mills</principal>
            <!-- what else do we want to include in title stmt? e.g. respstmt? -->
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Borås</publisher>
            <!-- publisher still to be decided authority tag? distributor tags? -->
            <date>March 2022</date>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">
                  <!-- do we want to have a CC licence? -->
                  <p> Transcription distributed under a CC-BY-SA 4.0 license. </p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>A post-it with a simple example phrase on it</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="WD" medium="blue-ink">Original text in blue ink, written by Wout
               Dillen.</handNote>
         </handNotes>
         <correspDesc>
            <correspAction>
               <persName><!-- complete info here - check TEI guideslines for correspDesc --></persName>
            </correspAction>
         </correspDesc>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface xml:id="postit01">
         <figure>
            <label>Post-It 01</label>
            <figDesc> A photograph of a post-it with a simple example phrase. </figDesc>
            <graphic xml:id="postit01_full" url="assets/img/documents/postit01.png"/>
            <graphic xml:id="postit01_thumb" url="assets/img/documents/postit01_thumb.png"/>
         </figure>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div n="1" type="letter" hand="#JM">
            <pb facs="#postit01"/>
            <!-- insert page location here -->
            <!-- insert correct image here -->
            <head>Letter 1 - Saturday Evening</head>
            
            <fw>
               <orgName rend="topLeft" type="preprintedText" rendition="capitalLetters">>METHODIST
                  GUILD <lb/>
                  <hi rend="u">HOLIDAYS</hi>.</orgName>
               <lb/>
               <num rend="topLeft" type="preprintedText">TELEPHONE DUNOON 234.</num>
               <location rend="topRight" type="preprintedText" rendition="capitalLetters">
                  <!-- check rend vs rendition -->
                  <address>
                     <placeName>DHALLING MHOR</placeName>
                     <addrLine>KIRN,</addrLine>
                     <addrLine>DUNOON,</addrLine>
                     <addrLine>ARGYLL.</addrLine>
                  </address>
               </location>
            </fw>
            <opener>
               <time rend="right" type="handWrittenText">Saturday <hi rend="u">Evening</hi>.</time>
               <salute rend="left">My Dear Doreen,</salute>
            </opener>
            
            <p>Dhalling Mhor doesn’t seem like Dhalling <lb/> Mhor now you are not here. You had
               become so <lb/> much a part of the life here, so far as I was <lb/> concerned, that
               things seem a bit dead now<lb/> you have gone.</p>
            <p>By this time you will be at home<lb/> or very near home (time six o’clock) and
               looking mournfully at the weather; it’s bound to be raining<lb/> in Manchester as it
               is here still. You have been<lb/> much in my thoughts as you made the beastly<lb/>
               railway journey and I kept saying to myself, “They<lb/> will have reached Glasgow
               now; they will be on the<lb/> M/C train now.”</p>
            <p> I can’t say how much I’ve missed<lb/> you today. I’ve wondered round a bit on my own,<lb/>
               <pb facs="xxx"/><!-- enter correct page here --> and played cards a bit with the
               older generation,<lb/> and slept a bit. Harry and Ellie, Jack and<lb/> Jean wanted me
               to go to the pictures with<lb/> them but as they were going to see <name><title
                  type="film">Gert and<lb/> Daisy</title></name> I declined the invitation.</p>
            <p>I’ve moved my belongings into room 13<lb/> and find it’s a delightful room with a
               nice<lb/> thick carpet which is much better than the<lb/> thin, loose mats to which
               you and I have<lb/> been used to hitherto. No doubt John<lb/> and I will do much
               talking about Ruby<lb/> and ______ (well don’t be surprised if you ears<lb/> burn a
               bit, too).</p>
            <p>There was a letter here for Poppy.<lb/> Mr. Henderson and I were re-addressing them
               and it’s<lb/> been sent on to your house; your address was<lb/> the one given in the
               visitors book; remember?<lb/> You will be able to pass it on to Poppy.<lb/> You might
               note <!-- look up note for squiggle --> that the stamp is placed<lb/><pb facs="xxx"/><!-- insert correct page here -->
               <fw>
                  <orgName rend="topLeft" type="preprintedText" rendition="capitalLetters"
                     >>METHODIST GUILD <lb/>
                     <hi rend="u">HOLIDAYS</hi>.</orgName>
                  <lb/>
                  <num rend="topLeft" type="preprintedText">TELEPHONE DUNOON 234.</num>
                  <location rend="topRight" type="preprintedText" rendition="capitalLetters">
                     <!-- check rend vs rendition -->
                     <address>
                        <placeName>DHALLING MHOR</placeName>
                        <addrLine>KIRN,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>DUNOON,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>ARGYLL.</addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </location>
               </fw>
               <metamark function="pageNumber" place="topLeft"><hi rend="u">2.</hi></metamark>
               crookedly and no doubt will bring a blush to<lb/> her cheek - that is, if it’s from
               the right<lb/> person.</p>
            <p>The new guests have been rolling up<lb/> looking <del type="strikeThrough">bedg</del>
               bedraggled, weary, worn and wet; but<lb/> I haven’t got to know any of them yet,<lb/>
               and there are more coming I know.<lb/>
            </p>
            <p>Let me know, Doreen, how you got<lb/> along today. You know, surely, that I
               shall<lb/> always be glad to hear from you and don’t<lb/> forget the tea. I looked in
               my diary and<lb/> found that Sept. 7th. is the date of the Harvest<lb/> Festival
               Lecture at the mission so please <sic>stear</sic><lb/> clear of that date, won’t you?
               I shall<lb/> count the days to Sept. with keen anticipation.<lb/> Don’t do too much
               work next week if you<lb/> don’t feel like it; I’ll give you permission to<lb/>
               <pb facs="xxx"/>
               <!-- insert correct page here --> slack but don’t let the boss see you. Think<lb/> of
               me on the hills (that’s where I shan’t<lb/> be if it keeps raining).<lb/>
            </p>
            <p>I ought to have said this morning,<lb/> ‘Thanks for helping to make my week’s
               stay<lb/> at Dhalling Mhor such a happy one.’ This<lb/> second week will not be as
               happy as the<lb/> first, I know. Do accept my thanks,<lb/> now. I feel so glad that
               the week<lb/> afforded to us the opportunity of each other’s<lb/> company &amp; I
               hope we shall continue the<lb/> friendship.<lb/>
            </p>
            
            <closer>
               <salute>Every good wish to you, Doreen.<lb/> Your very sincere friend,</salute>
               <signed>
                  <hi rend="u"/>Jim.</signed>
               <pb/>
            </closer>
         </div>
         
         <div type="envelope">
            <pb facs="xxx"/><!-- insert correct image here -->
            <metamark><hi rend="u"></hi>1</metamark>
            <metamark place="topLeft">
               <stamp>Manchester postal stamp</stamp>
            </metamark>
            <metamark place="topRight">
               <stamp>two postage stamps</stamp>
            </metamark>
          
            <p>
               <address>
                  <addrLine>Rev. James Mills,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine rend="capitalLetters">"DHALLING MHOR",</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>Kirn,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>nr. Dunoon,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>Argyllshire,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine rend="capitalLetters">SCOTLAND</addrLine>
               </address>
            </p>
            <pb/><!-- insert back of envelope here -->
            <p>XXXXXXXXXXXXXXX<lb/>XXXXXXXXXXX<lb/>XXXXXXXXXXXXXXX</p>
            <metamark place="centre" function="seal"><note>a red wax seal</note></metamark> <!-- do we want this information here or all in physDesc in header or both? -->
         </div>
         
         <div type="letter" n="2" hand="#DB">
            <opener>
               <address rend="topRight"> <!-- is it ok to use rend for location on page? -->
                  <addrLine>"Edale",</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>2, Cranbourne Road,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>Chortlton-cum-Hardy,</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>Manchester, 21,</addrLine>
                 </address>
               <dateline><hi rend="u">Tuesday.</hi></dateline>
               <salute>My dear Jim,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               
               Thank you ever so much for the nice letter which you sent me. It was good of you to write so soon. I, too, must say that it has been the most delightful holiday I have ever spent, and would express my sincere thanks for the very happy times which we had together. 
               
               I have been into the office, and have now got settled down somewhat, but all the same, I can’t help wishing I was back at Dhalling Mhor! 
               
               We were late arriving in Manchester on Saturday. We got in about 7.0. instead of 5.0. You were quite right in supposing that it would be raining. It certainly was, and I do not think it has stopped since. 
               
               I received Poppy’s letter here, and have forwarded it on to her, thank you. 
               
               I am sending you a photograph ,which was recently taken, if you care to have it, as I think it is a bit better than the one we had taken at Dunoon?
               
               Enclosed you will find my  £ 3., as I cannot spend them here without losing on them ( I have cultivated the Scotch habit, haven’t I?)
               
               Perhaps we could have the 21st “do”on the 12th September, if this will be convenient to you. However, let me know, and then we can fix it. 
               
               If ever you are in Manchester before then, do not hesitate to go into the Central Hall and see Dad, as I am sure he will be pleased to meet you. 
               
               I have been looking at the photograph of Swanwick - 1939- and notice both you and Dad on it, so, no doubt, you will recognise him when you see him. 
               
               Well Jim! I do hope you have a really good holiday, and that you will feel much better for it when you come back. 
               
               I trust the weather will improve. Please give my kind regards to Jack and Jean, Harry &amp; Ellie, and, of course, John. Do not stay awake talking all night, will you? Dad was enquiring about Ruby, and they said she will have to see a specialist, as it will probably need an operation. 
               
               All the very best, and hoping to see you soon. 
               Yours very sincerely, 
               Doreen 
               
               
            </p>
            
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>